the even and all of integers are
familiar concepts to us however in this
particular video what we're going to do
is we're going to try to define exactly
what we mean by the even and odd
integers we're going to try to have the
most precise and formal and rigorous
definition of these concepts that we can
have and the idea is this when we're
trying to make claims about mathematics
and when we're trying to prove claims in
mathematics we need to have a high
degree of precision and simply saying we
understand what even numbers are their
numbers like two four six eight and
seeing that we understand what odd
numbers like three five seven and nine
are is insufficient we need to use
incredibly precise ideas for what these
concepts actually are now when I look at
this in formal definition there's a sort
of existential nature to it when we say
that an integer say n can be written as
twice something really what we're saying
is that there exists this existential
claim there exists some other integer K
where the N can be written as twice at
so if I want to take this informal
definition and make it into a formal one
I might write something like this I
would say that n is an integer if there
exists another integer K so so there
exists a K any integers but has the
property that the N is twice K now why
do I like this formal definition so much
it's because now there's actually an
equation here N equals to K and I know
something about what K is K is an
integer
so if I want to make a proof that
involves the even integers now I can
actually substitute it in I can write
equation I have a precise way of writing
what I mean when I talk about an even
integer ok same story but for the
auditors well okay what's an odd integer
informally odd integers are the integers
that are just not even as in if two four
six eight are even integers then the
other ones though the one three five
seven
those are the auditors
you are allowed to define something as
being not some other thing okay but
let's try to be a little bit more
precise about this if I take say six we
said that was even because it was twice
an integer but what about seven so seven
is odd but what I notice about seven is
that it's twice an integer twice three
plus one so all of the odd integers can
really be written as twice an integer
plus one so I maybe use that as my
formal definition again it's an
existential claim I'm saying there
exists a cave in the integers such that
your audience a Duran can be written as
twice K plus one and now again I have a
precise formal definition of what I mean
by all integers there's an equation here
I can send it to that equation into
other equations that I can use these
definitions to make proofs about the
even and odd integers and indeed in the
next video that's exactly what I'm going
to do I'm going to do our first proof
and I'm going to use these definitions
of even and odd in the proof that I'm
going to do in the next video